## **Dean Jones**

16 Woodstock Rd SW, Calgary, AB | (587)433-5825 djones 09 riseball@hotmail.com | LinkedIn

# **Piping Designer**

I have been providing drafting and piping design services for over fifteen years. I have experience with the complete life-cycle of a project and can ensure accuracy and cost-effectiveness. I have a unique set of skills that have proved invaluable in producing professional results.

## Skills and Software

AutoCAD	Checking	P&ID's	Standards & Specs
CADworx	2D/3D Modelling	Mentoring	Regulatory
ProCAD	Piping Design	Drafting Standards	Typing (50 wpm)
Plant 3D	Navisworks	Oil & Gas Design	Autolisp
Smart P&ID's	Isogen	Pipelines	Scripting
AutoPlant	Excel	Wellsites	Customization
SQL Database	Bluebeam PDF	Compressor Station	Software Developer

# **Highlighted Career Achievements**

- Successfully worked in a fast-paced environment.
- Continually exceeded expectations and delivered quality results on-time.
- Demonstrated ability to pick-up new software quickly.

### **AutoCAD Expert & CAD Support:**

- Formally trained in AutoCAD, my extensive experience and knowledge has created the ability to find solutions to many problems. I can provide many additional tools through customization of AutoCAD increasing efficiency to my workflow as well as colleagues which saves time and money.

## **Ring Border Program:**

- Provided upstream drafting and design of drawings and typicals for wellsite and pipeline tie-ins for the Ring Border Plant annually. I completed the designs for up to seventy new wellsites in four months including as-builts.

#### **Twin Reboiler Project:**

- Provided the 3D modeling for a \$3MM project using CADworx. The model consisted of all equipment, piping design and structural steel. The project design was finalized in six weeks saving an estimated 10% in construction costs.

#### **Team Skills:**

- Authored department standards and software specifications in multiple job roles.
- Composed numerous scripts effectively saving hundreds of man-hours.
- Maintained and setup in-house software systems creating a coherent work environment.
- Trained and mentored a large office providing excellent software support.
- Successfully worked remotely for over two years.

### **Education**

SAIT - Engineering Design & Drafting Technology (*Process Piping*) Sep 1994 - Apr 1996 SAIT - Object Oriented Software Developer Certification (*OOSD*) Oct 2016 - Jul 2017

# **Dean Jones**

Page 2

# **Professional Experience**

## **Rangeland Engineering - Senior Piping Lead**

June 2015 - Feb 2016

- Streamlined the P&ID group after stepping in as lead.
- Administered back-end P&ID support for Plant 3D software.
- Managed a small team, organizing and optimizing to eliminate errors on deliverables.

### **Three Streams Engineering - CAD Support Specialist**

**July 2012 - Feb 2015** 

- Participated on daily CAD tickets servicing a large office supporting multiple disciplines and software.
- Mentored and advised junior drafters.
- Implemented routine file cleanup using scripts on CADworx and AutoPlant drawings.
- Generated SQL reports for weekly model reviews.
- Consistently delivered solutions and troubleshooted complex CAD problems.

### ConocoPhillips Canada - Senior Piping Lead

May 2006 - July 2012

- Developed drafting standards manual to improve quality control on drawings.
- Acted as Drawing Coordinator, Senior Drafter and CAD support for drafting group in Western Canada.
- Centralized startup script optimizing consistency and improving implementation time.
- Maintained and setup CAD systems and software, blocks, titleblocks, templates and specifications.
- Formulated several customizations in AutoCAD and ProCAD, including scripts, macros and Autolisp programs to increase efficiency and eliminate errors.

## Samson Canada - Piping Designer

Nov 2004 - Apr 2006

- Worked in a small team environment completing entire piping design packages, including piles and pipe supports for wellsites and compressors stations.

### Rangeland Engineering - Piping Designer

Mar 2004 - Oct 2004

- 2D/3D modelling and piping designs with CADworx and ProCAD.
- Setup specifications for CADworx.
- Managed CAD systems.

## **Techskill - Piping Designer**

Feb 2002 - Feb 2004

- Completed field sketches and validation for as-builts.
- Designed 2D and 3D equipment, internals and piping designs using ProCAD and CADworx.
- Provided structural steel designs for facility platforms, stairs, and building details.
- Specialized in pile layouts and steel pipe support designs.

## SEAL International - Junior Draftsman

Mar 2000 - Aug 2001

- Gained valuable experience in process and instrumentation on HAZOP P&ID's.

#### **SNC Lavalin - Junior Draftsman**

Oct 1997 - Feb 2000

- Processed initial mechanical design on P&ID's for billion-dollar major oilsands project.
- 3D modelling of all major equipment.
- Back-end support to senior designers with isogen.